A Guide to the Martha Eheart King Papers, 1728-1990
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Martha Eheart King Papers, 1728-1990
The Library of Virginia
51741
4 cubic feet (10 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mr. and Mrs. William W. Harlowe, Troy.
Biographical Information
Martha Katherine Eheart was born in Charlottesville, Virginia on 17 May 1923. She was the daughter of Robert Lee Eheart (1897-1951) and Mary Marguerite Harlowe (1900-1995). She married James Edward King on 27 August 1942. They resided in Manassas, where she published two genealogical books and contributed articles to several publications, and was a certified genealogist and member of the Daughters of the American Revolution and the United Daughters of the Confederacy. Martha Eheart King died on 6 July 2013 and is buried in Riverview Cemetery in Charlottesville.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1728-1990, of Martha Eheart King (1923-2013) of Warrenton, Virginia, including research files for her two books Harlow-Harlowe: Descendants of Henry Martin and Mary Elizabeth (Hawley) Harlow (1980) and "Dear Bennie": Letters of Mollie (Slusher) Garr and Alice Garr of Lafayette County, Missouri to William Benjamin Plunkett of Greene County, Virginia, 1880-1896 (1982), as well as Plunkett family papers and subject files.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
I. Harlow-Harlowe: Descendants of Henry Martin and Mary Elizabeth (Hawley) Harlow Research Files.
II. "Dear Bennie": Letters of Mollie (Slusher) Garr and Alice Garr of Lafayette County, Missouri to William Benjamin Plunkett of Greene County, Virginia, 1880-1896 Research Files.
III. Plunkett Family Papers.
IV. Subject Files.
Contents List
- Series I. Harlow-Harlowe: Descendants of Henry Martin and Mary Elizabeth (Hawley) Harlow Research Files., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 1-2)
  The research files contain abstracts, copies, and transcriptions of census records, chancery cases, deeds, estate administration records, military records, vital statistics, and wills. There is also correspondence, family group sheets, genealogical notes, information from published sources, questionnaires, research notes, final typescripts, and material related to the publishing, printing, and ordering of the book.
  - Census Abtracts. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Eheart. (Box 1, Folder 2-4)
  - Eheart and Related Lines1859. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Eheart - Wills - Orange County. (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
  - Estate of Adam Ehart. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Harlow-Harlowe. (Box 1, Folder 9-11)
  - Harrison. (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
  - Publishing and Press. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Questionnaires. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Thurman. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Typescript. (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
  - Wheeler, John V. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Wood. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Series II. Subject Files, 1816-1903., Extent: 4 boxes. (Box 9-12)
  The subject files contain accounts and receipts, agreements and contracts, bank books, commonplace books of Otway H. Chalkley (1830-1883), genealogical notes on the Jordan and Taylor families, fraternal and masonic materials, insurance papers, legal notes and suit papers, memorandum books, programs, tax receipts, and information on the Virginia State Good Roads Association.
  - Accounts and Receipts, 1889-1897. (Box 9, Folder 4-13)
  - Accounts and Receipts, 1898-1903. (Box 10, Folder 1-7)
  - Accounts and Receipts, No Date/Year. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Acts of 1897-1898. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Agreements/Contracts. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Armstrong, John, Jr. - Letter, 4 October 1814 (Typescript). (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Augusta White Lithia Water. (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Bank Books. (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Billfolds. (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Bolivar School Precinct Petition. (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Book Price Lists and Catalogues. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Burton & Williams. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Business/Trade/Calling Cards. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Cash Book, 1873. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - "Chain Gang" Reports. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Checkbook Registers. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Clerk's Correspondence and Court Papers, 1816-1857. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Clippings. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Commonplace Books (O. H. Chalkley). (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Composition - "Told in the Twilight". (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Covington Circulating Library. (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Deeds. (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Deposition. (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Dismissal Letter, 1885. (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Emmanuel Episcopal Church. (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Estate of Susan M. Chalkley. (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - The Farmer's Wife - Prizes. (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Harper v. Magruder. (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Huddlestun v. Howard & Sears. (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Insurance. (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Invitations. (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Jordan. (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Julius Hines & Son - Prce List. (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Ker, Abel Upshur. (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Knights of Pythias. (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Knights Templar. (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Law Licenses. (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Legal Notes. (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Legislation - Act to Regulate Immigration of Aliens. (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Legislation - Enlargement of Staunton Corporate Limits. (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Legislation - Increase Highland County Court Judge Salary. (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Letterhead Samples. (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Mechanics' Building Association. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Memorandum/Scrapbook. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Memorandum Books. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Military Discharge, 1881. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Mutual Guarantee Building and Loan Association. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - National Surety Company of New York. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Packing List, 1889. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Petitions for Official Appointments. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Phi Beta Kappa. (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Phi Delta Theta. (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Photograph (Small Girl - Unidentified). (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Photograph Album (Foreign). (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Prison Association of Virginia. (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Programs. (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Qualification of County Clerk and District Officers, 1893. (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Railroad Passes. (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Receipts and Expenditures, 1895-1896. (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Road Closure Application. (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Royal Arcanum. (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Security Savings and Loan Association (Mobile, AL). (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Stock Certificate - Staunton Building Company. (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Suit Papers. (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Summonses. (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Tax Receipts. (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Taylor. (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Tenant Book, 1896. (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Treasurers Receipts, 1921-1922. (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - University College of Medicine - Teaching Methods. (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Virginia State Good Roads Association. (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Withdrawal from University of Virginia, 1880. (Box 12, Folder 31)